<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<!DOCTYPE Chapter [
	<!ATTLIST Chapter ChapterID CDATA #REQUIRED>
	<!ATTLIST Chapter ChapterName CDATA #REQUIRED>
	<!ELEMENT Chapter (Verse+)>
	<!ATTLIST Verse VerseID CDATA #REQUIRED>
	<!ELEMENT Verse (#PCDATA)>
]>
<!-- This SQL Query Generated at 03 February 2014 07:40 (UTC) from www.qurandatabase.org -->
<Chapter ChapterID="26" ChapterName="The Poets">
	<Verse VerseID="1"><![CDATA[Ta. Sin. Mim.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="2"><![CDATA[These are verses of the Book that makes (things) clear.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="3"><![CDATA[It may be thou frettest thy soul with grief, that they do not become Believers.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="4"><![CDATA[If (such) were Our Will, We could send down to them from the sky a Sign, to which they would bend their necks in humility.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="5"><![CDATA[But there comes not to them a newly-revealed Message from (Allah) Most Gracious, but they turn away therefrom.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="6"><![CDATA[They have indeed rejected (the Message): so they will know soon (enough) the truth of what they mocked at!]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="7"><![CDATA[Do they not look at the earth,- how many noble things of all kinds We have produced therein?]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="8"><![CDATA[Verily, in this is a Sign: but most of them do not believe.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="9"><![CDATA[And verily, thy Lord is He, the Exalted in Might, Most Merciful.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="10"><![CDATA[Behold, thy Lord called Moses: "Go to the people of iniquity,-]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="11"><![CDATA["The people of the Pharaoh: will they not fear Allah?"]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="12"><![CDATA[He said: "O my Lord! I do fear that they will charge me with falsehood:]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="13"><![CDATA["My breast will be straitened. And my speech may not go (smoothly): so send unto Aaron.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="14"><![CDATA["And (further), they have a charge of crime against me; and I fear they may slay me."]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="15"><![CDATA[Allah said: "By no means! proceed then, both of you, with Our Signs; We are with you, and will listen (to your call).]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="16"><![CDATA["So go forth, both of you, to Pharaoh, and say: ´We have been sent by the Lord and Cherisher of the worlds;]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="17"><![CDATA["´Send thou with us the Children of Israel.´"]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="18"><![CDATA[(Pharaoh) said: "Did we not cherish thee as a child among us, and didst thou not stay in our midst many years of thy life?]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="19"><![CDATA["And thou didst a deed of thine which (thou knowest) thou didst, and thou art an ungrateful (wretch)!"]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="20"><![CDATA[Moses said: "I did it then, when I was in error.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="21"><![CDATA["So I fled from you (all) when I feared you; but my Lord has (since) invested me with judgment (and wisdom) and appointed me as one of the messengers.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="22"><![CDATA["And this is the favour with which thou dost reproach me,- that thou hast enslaved the Children of Israel!"]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="23"><![CDATA[Pharaoh said: "And what is the ´Lord and Cherisher of the worlds´?"]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="24"><![CDATA[(Moses) said: "The Lord and Cherisher of the heavens and the earth, and all between,- if ye want to be quite sure."]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="25"><![CDATA[(Pharaoh) said to those around: "Did ye not listen (to what he says)?"]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="26"><![CDATA[(Moses) said: "Your Lord and the Lord of your fathers from the beginning!"]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="27"><![CDATA[(Pharaoh) said: "Truly your messenger who has been sent to you is a veritable madman!"]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="28"><![CDATA[(Moses) said: "Lord of the East and the West, and all between! if ye only had sense!"]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="29"><![CDATA[(Pharaoh) said: "If thou dost put forward any god other than me, I will certainly put thee in prison!"]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="30"><![CDATA[(Moses) said: "Even if I showed you something clear (and) convincing?"]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="31"><![CDATA[(Pharaoh) said: "Show it then, if thou tellest the truth!"]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="32"><![CDATA[So (Moses) threw his rod, and behold, it was a serpent, plain (for all to see)!]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="33"><![CDATA[And he drew out his hand, and behold, it was white to all beholders!]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="34"><![CDATA[(Pharaoh) said to the Chiefs around him: "This is indeed a sorcerer well-versed:]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="35"><![CDATA["His plan is to get you out of your land by his sorcery; then what is it ye counsel?"]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="36"><![CDATA[They said: "Keep him and his brother in suspense (for a while), and dispatch to the Cities heralds to collect-]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="37"><![CDATA["And bring up to thee all (our) sorcerers well-versed."]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="38"><![CDATA[So the sorcerers were got together for the appointment of a day well-known,]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="39"><![CDATA[And the people were told: "Are ye (now) assembled?-]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="40"><![CDATA["That we may follow the sorcerers (in religion) if they win?"]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="41"><![CDATA[So when the sorcerers arrived, they said to Pharaoh: "Of course - shall we have a (suitable) reward if we win?]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="42"><![CDATA[He said: "Yea, (and more),- for ye shall in that case be (raised to posts) nearest (to my person)."]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="43"><![CDATA[Moses said to them: "Throw ye - that which ye are about to throw!"]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="44"><![CDATA[So they threw their ropes and their rods, and said: "By the might of Pharaoh, it is we who will certainly win!"]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="45"><![CDATA[Then Moses threw his rod, when, behold, it straightway swallows up all the falsehoods which they fake!]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="46"><![CDATA[Then did the sorcerers fall down, prostrate in adoration,]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="47"><![CDATA[Saying: "We believe in the Lord of the Worlds,]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="48"><![CDATA["The Lord of Moses and Aaron."]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="49"><![CDATA[Said (Pharaoh): "Believe ye in Him before I give you permission? surely he is your leader, who has taught you sorcery! but soon shall ye know! Be sure I will cut off your hands and your feet on opposite sides, and I will cause you all to die on the cross!"]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="50"><![CDATA[They said: "No matter! for us, we shall but return to our Lord!]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="51"><![CDATA["Only, our desire is that our Lord will forgive us our faults, that we may become foremost among the believers!"]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="52"><![CDATA[By inspiration we told Moses: "Travel by night with my servants; for surely ye shall be pursued."]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="53"><![CDATA[Then Pharaoh sent heralds to (all) the Cities,]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="54"><![CDATA[(Saying): "These (Israelites) are but a small band,]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="55"><![CDATA["And they are raging furiously against us;]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="56"><![CDATA["But we are a multitude amply fore-warned."]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="57"><![CDATA[So We expelled them from gardens, springs,]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="58"><![CDATA[Treasures, and every kind of honourable position;]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="59"><![CDATA[Thus it was, but We made the Children of Israel inheritors of such things.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="60"><![CDATA[So they pursued them at sunrise.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="61"><![CDATA[And when the two bodies saw each other, the people of Moses said: "We are sure to be overtaken."]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="62"><![CDATA[(Moses) said: "By no means! my Lord is with me! Soon will He guide me!"]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="63"><![CDATA[Then We told Moses by inspiration: "Strike the sea with thy rod." So it divided, and each separate part became like the huge, firm mass of a mountain.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="64"><![CDATA[And We made the other party approach thither.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="65"><![CDATA[We delivered Moses and all who were with him;]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="66"><![CDATA[But We drowned the others.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="67"><![CDATA[Verily in this is a Sign: but most of them do not believe.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="68"><![CDATA[And verily thy Lord is He, the Exalted in Might, Most Merciful.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="69"><![CDATA[And rehearse to them (something of) Abraham´s story.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="70"><![CDATA[Behold, he said to his father and his people: "What worship ye?"]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="71"><![CDATA[They said: "We worship idols, and we remain constantly in attendance on them."]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="72"><![CDATA[He said: "Do they listen to you when ye call (on them)?"]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="73"><![CDATA["Or do you good or harm?"]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="74"><![CDATA[They said: "Nay, but we found our fathers doing thus (what we do)."]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="75"><![CDATA[He said: "Do ye then see whom ye have been worshipping,-]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="76"><![CDATA["Ye and your fathers before you?-]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="77"><![CDATA["For they are enemies to me; not so the Lord and Cherisher of the Worlds;]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="78"><![CDATA["Who created me, and it is He Who guides me;]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="79"><![CDATA["Who gives me food and drink,]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="80"><![CDATA["And when I am ill, it is He Who cures me;]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="81"><![CDATA["Who will cause me to die, and then to life (again);]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="82"><![CDATA["And who, I hope, will forgive me my faults on the day of Judgment.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="83"><![CDATA["O my Lord! bestow wisdom on me, and join me with the righteous;]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="84"><![CDATA["Grant me honourable mention on the tongue of truth among the latest (generations);]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="85"><![CDATA["Make me one of the inheritors of the Garden of Bliss;]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="86"><![CDATA["Forgive my father, for that he is among those astray;]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="87"><![CDATA["And let me not be in disgrace on the Day when (men) will be raised up;-]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="88"><![CDATA["The Day whereon neither wealth nor sons will avail,]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="89"><![CDATA["But only he (will prosper) that brings to Allah a sound heart;]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="90"><![CDATA["To the righteous, the Garden will be brought near,]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="91"><![CDATA["And to those straying in Evil, the Fire will be placed in full view;]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="92"><![CDATA["And it shall be said to them: ´Where are the (gods) ye worshipped-]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="93"><![CDATA["´Besides Allah? Can they help you or help themselves?´]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="94"><![CDATA["Then they will be thrown headlong into the (Fire),- they and those straying in Evil,]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="95"><![CDATA["And the whole hosts of Iblis together.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="96"><![CDATA["They will say there in their mutual bickerings:]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="97"><![CDATA["´By Allah, we were truly in an error manifest,]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="98"><![CDATA["´When we held you as equals with the Lord of the Worlds;]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="99"><![CDATA["´And our seducers were only those who were steeped in guilt.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="100"><![CDATA["´Now, then, we have none to intercede (for us),]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="101"><![CDATA["´Nor a single friend to feel (for us).]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="102"><![CDATA["´Now if we only had a chance of return we shall truly be of those who believe!´"]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="103"><![CDATA[Verily in this is a Sign but most of them do not believe.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="104"><![CDATA[And verily thy Lord is He, the Exalted in Might, Most Merciful.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="105"><![CDATA[The people of Noah rejected the messengers.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="106"><![CDATA[Behold, their brother Noah said to them: "Will ye not fear (Allah)?]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="107"><![CDATA["I am to you a messenger worthy of all trust:]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="108"><![CDATA["So fear Allah, and obey me.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="109"><![CDATA["No reward do I ask of you for it: my reward is only from the Lord of the Worlds:]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="110"><![CDATA["So fear Allah, and obey me."]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="111"><![CDATA[They said: "Shall we believe in thee when it is the meanest that follow thee?"]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="112"><![CDATA[He said: "And what do I know as to what they do?]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="113"><![CDATA["Their account is only with my Lord, if ye could (but) understand.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="114"><![CDATA["I am not one to drive away those who believe.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="115"><![CDATA["I am sent only to warn plainly in public."]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="116"><![CDATA[They said: "If thou desist not, O Noah! thou shalt be stoned (to death)."]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="117"><![CDATA[He said: "O my Lord! truly my people have rejected me.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="118"><![CDATA["Judge Thou, then, between me and them openly, and deliver me and those of the Believers who are with me."]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="119"><![CDATA[So We delivered him and those with him, in the Ark filled (with all creatures).]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="120"><![CDATA[Thereafter We drowned those who remained behind.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="121"><![CDATA[Verily in this is a Sign: but most of them do not believe.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="122"><![CDATA[And verily thy Lord is He, the Exalted in Might, Most Merciful.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="123"><![CDATA[The ´Ad (people) rejected the messengers.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="124"><![CDATA[Behold, their brother Hud said to them: "Will ye not fear (Allah)?]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="125"><![CDATA["I am to you a messenger worthy of all trust:]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="126"><![CDATA["So fear Allah and obey me.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="127"><![CDATA["No reward do I ask of you for it: my reward is only from the Lord of the Worlds.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="128"><![CDATA["Do ye build a landmark on every high place to amuse yourselves?]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="129"><![CDATA["And do ye get for yourselves fine buildings in the hope of living therein (for ever)?]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="130"><![CDATA["And when ye exert your strong hand, do ye do it like men of absolute power?]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="131"><![CDATA["Now fear Allah, and obey me.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="132"><![CDATA["Yea, fear Him Who has bestowed on you freely all that ye know.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="133"><![CDATA["Freely has He bestowed on you cattle and sons,-]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="134"><![CDATA["And Gardens and Springs.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="135"><![CDATA["Truly I fear for you the Penalty of a Great Day."]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="136"><![CDATA[They said: "It is the same to us whether thou admonish us or be not among (our) admonishers!]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="137"><![CDATA["This is no other than a customary device of the ancients,]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="138"><![CDATA["And we are not the ones to receive Pains and Penalties!"]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="139"><![CDATA[So they rejected him, and We destroyed them. Verily in this is a Sign: but most of them do not believe.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="140"><![CDATA[And verily thy Lord is He, the Exalted in Might, Most Merciful.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="141"><![CDATA[The Thamud (people) rejected the messengers.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="142"><![CDATA[Behold, their brother Salih said to them: "Will you not fear (Allah)?]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="143"><![CDATA["I am to you a messenger worthy of all trust.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="144"><![CDATA["So fear Allah, and obey me.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="145"><![CDATA["No reward do I ask of you for it: my reward is only from the Lord of the Worlds.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="146"><![CDATA["Will ye be left secure, in (the enjoyment of) all that ye have here?-]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="147"><![CDATA["Gardens and Springs,]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="148"><![CDATA["And corn-fields and date-palms with spathes near breaking (with the weight of fruit)?]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="149"><![CDATA["And ye carve houses out of (rocky) mountains with great skill.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="150"><![CDATA["But fear Allah and obey me;]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="151"><![CDATA["And follow not the bidding of those who are extravagant,-]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="152"><![CDATA["Who make mischief in the land, and mend not (their ways)."]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="153"><![CDATA[They said: "Thou art only one of those bewitched!]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="154"><![CDATA["Thou art no more than a mortal like us: then bring us a Sign, if thou tellest the truth!"]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="155"><![CDATA[He said: "Here is a she-camel: she has a right of watering, and ye have a right of watering, (severally) on a day appointed.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="156"><![CDATA["Touch her not with harm, lest the Penalty of a Great Day seize you."]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="157"><![CDATA[But they ham-strung her: then did they become full of regrets.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="158"><![CDATA[But the Penalty seized them. Verily in this is a Sign: but most of them do not believe.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="159"><![CDATA[And verily thy Lord is He, the Exalted in Might, Most Merciful.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="160"><![CDATA[The people of Lut rejected the messengers.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="161"><![CDATA[Behold, their brother Lut said to them: "Will ye not fear (Allah)?]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="162"><![CDATA["I am to you a messenger worthy of all trust.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="163"><![CDATA["So fear Allah and obey me.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="164"><![CDATA["No reward do I ask of you for it: my reward is only from the lord of the Worlds.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="165"><![CDATA["Of all the creatures in the world, will ye approach males,]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="166"><![CDATA["And leave those whom Allah has created for you to be your mates? Nay, ye are a people transgressing (all limits)!"]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="167"><![CDATA[They said: "If thou desist not, O Lut! thou wilt assuredly be cast out!"]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="168"><![CDATA[He said: "I do detest your doings."]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="169"><![CDATA["O my Lord! deliver me and my family from such things as they do!"]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="170"><![CDATA[So We delivered him and his family,- all]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="171"><![CDATA[Except an old woman who lingered behind.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="172"><![CDATA[But the rest We destroyed utterly.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="173"><![CDATA[We rained down on them a shower (of brimstone): and evil was the shower on those who were admonished (but heeded not)!]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="174"><![CDATA[Verily in this is a Sign: but most of them do not believe.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="175"><![CDATA[And verily thy Lord is He, the Exalted in Might Most Merciful.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="176"><![CDATA[The Companions of the Wood rejected the messengers.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="177"><![CDATA[Behold, Shu´aib said to them: "Will ye not fear (Allah)?]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="178"><![CDATA["I am to you a messenger worthy of all trust.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="179"><![CDATA["So fear Allah and obey me.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="180"><![CDATA["No reward do I ask of you for it: my reward is only from the Lord of the Worlds.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="181"><![CDATA["Give just measure, and cause no loss (to others by fraud).]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="182"><![CDATA["And weigh with scales true and upright.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="183"><![CDATA["And withhold not things justly due to men, nor do evil in the land, working mischief.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="184"><![CDATA["And fear Him Who created you and (who created) the generations before (you)"]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="185"><![CDATA[They said: "Thou art only one of those bewitched!]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="186"><![CDATA["Thou art no more than a mortal like us, and indeed we think thou art a liar!]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="187"><![CDATA["Now cause a piece of the sky to fall on us, if thou art truthful!"]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="188"><![CDATA[He said: "My Lord knows best what ye do."]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="189"><![CDATA[But they rejected him. Then the punishment of a day of overshadowing gloom seized them, and that was the Penalty of a Great Day.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="190"><![CDATA[Verily in that is a Sign: but most of them do not believe.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="191"><![CDATA[And verily thy Lord is He, the Exalted in Might, Most Merciful.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="192"><![CDATA[Verily this is a Revelation from the Lord of the Worlds:]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="193"><![CDATA[With it came down the spirit of Faith and Truth-]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="194"><![CDATA[To thy heart and mind, that thou mayest admonish.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="195"><![CDATA[In the perspicuous Arabic tongue.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="196"><![CDATA[Without doubt it is (announced) in the mystic Books of former peoples.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="197"><![CDATA[Is it not a Sign to them that the Learned of the Children of Israel knew it (as true)?]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="198"><![CDATA[Had We revealed it to any of the non-Arabs,]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="199"><![CDATA[And had he recited it to them, they would not have believed in it.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="200"><![CDATA[Thus have We caused it to enter the hearts of the sinners.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="201"><![CDATA[They will not believe in it until they see the grievous Penalty;]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="202"><![CDATA[But the (Penalty) will come to them of a sudden, while they perceive it not;]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="203"><![CDATA[Then they will say: "Shall we be respited?"]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="204"><![CDATA[Do they then ask for Our Penalty to be hastened on?]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="205"><![CDATA[Seest thou? If We do let them enjoy (this life) for a few years,]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="206"><![CDATA[Yet there comes to them at length the (Punishment) which they were promised!]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="207"><![CDATA[It will profit them not that they enjoyed (this life)!]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="208"><![CDATA[Never did We destroy a population, but had its warners -]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="209"><![CDATA[By way of reminder; and We never are unjust.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="210"><![CDATA[No evil ones have brought down this (Revelation):]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="211"><![CDATA[It would neither suit them nor would they be able (to produce it).]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="212"><![CDATA[Indeed they have been removed far from even (a chance of) hearing it.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="213"><![CDATA[So call not on any other god with Allah, or thou wilt be among those under the Penalty.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="214"><![CDATA[And admonish thy nearest kinsmen,]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="215"><![CDATA[And lower thy wing to the Believers who follow thee.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="216"><![CDATA[Then if they disobey thee, say: "I am free (of responsibility) for what ye do!"]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="217"><![CDATA[And put thy trust on the Exalted in Might, the Merciful,-]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="218"><![CDATA[Who seeth thee standing forth (in prayer),]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="219"><![CDATA[And thy movements among those who prostrate themselves,]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="220"><![CDATA[For it is He Who heareth and knoweth all things.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="221"><![CDATA[Shall I inform you, (O people!), on whom it is that the evil ones descend?]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="222"><![CDATA[They descend on every lying, wicked person,]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="223"><![CDATA[(Into whose ears) they pour hearsay vanities, and most of them are liars.]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="224"><![CDATA[And the Poets,- It is those straying in Evil, who follow them:]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="225"><![CDATA[Seest thou not that they wander distracted in every valley?-]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="226"><![CDATA[And that they say what they practise not?-]]></Verse>
	<Verse VerseID="227"><![CDATA[Except those who believe, work righteousness, engage much in the remembrance of Allah, and defend themselves only after they are unjustly attacked. And soon will the unjust assailants know what vicissitudes their affairs will take!]]></Verse>
</Chapter>
